Contact

+39 3313628242 (Mobile) akrammahmoud.web@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/akrammahmoud (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Front-end Development Software Design Patterns JavaScript

Languages

Italian (Full Professional)
Arabic (Native or Bilingual)
English (Full Professional)

Certifications

with JavaScript ES6+

Up and Running with Git and GitHub
JavaScript Essential Training
Building Modern Projects with React
JavaScript: Test-Driven
Development (ES6)
Learning Functional Programming

Akram Mahmoud

Frontend Developer

Bologna, Emilia-Romagna, Italy

Summary

Key Skills:

Proficient in React, Styled-Component, TailwindCss, Material-UI, Node.js, WordPress, PHP

Experienced in AWS cloud architecture, serverless lambda, stepfunctions, SQS Messages queue

Proficient in Agile methodology and git-flow version control Knowledgeable in .NET MVC development

Strong attention to detail in ensuring website compatibility with major browsers and accessibility versions

Me: Quick learner, Good Communication, Flexible and adaptable to changes, Good listener, and Helpful without being asked

Overall, my experience has enabled me to develop a deep understanding of frontend web development and the importance of developing responsive, user-friendly interfaces. I am excited to bring my expertise and knowledge to your team and help drive success.

Experience

Jointly
Frontend Developer
December 2022 - Present (3 months)
Milan, Lombardy, Italy

Responsibilities:

- Developing and implementing complex React applications for welfare services.
- Collaborating with stakeholders and product owners to identify requirements and prioritize features.

- Designing and implementing user interfaces that are visually appealing and easy to use.
- Writing clean, maintainable, and well-documented code that adheres to industry best practices.
- Participating in code reviews to ensure code quality and compliance with team standards.
- Optimizing the application for maximum speed and scalability.
- Identifying and addressing technical debt to maintain code quality and performance.
- Keeping up-to-date with emerging trends and technologies in web development.
- Actively participating in team meetings, stand-ups, and other agile ceremonies.

ShopFully

Frontend Developer

March 2021 - December 2022 (1 year 10 months)

Bologna, Emilia-Romagna, Italy

- Developed and maintained an internal platform for marketing automation using Microservices, Microfrontend and AWS cloud architecture.
- Collaborated with a team to develop and maintain internal services integrated with Google ads & Facebook ads APIs
- Developed frontend using React and Material-UI and the backend with Node.js with serverless lambda and step-functions integration on AWS
- Managed SQS Messages queue and maintained/improved the PHP & CakePHP services
- Implemented Agile methodology and used git-flow for version control
- Created CI/CD pipeline for cloud application builds

YOOX NET-A-PORTER GROUP

Frontend Developer

May 2019 - April 2021 (2 years)

Zola Predosa, Emilia-Romagna, Italia

- Worked in a cross-functional team of 15 people to develop fashion online stores using .NET MVC
- Ensured website compatibility with major browsers and accessibility versions
- Maintained scalability and maintainability of website code
- Used git-flow methodology and managed teammates' code reviews
- Participated in YNAP's web technology training courses

Nexus Web Agency Frontend Developer April 2018 - May 2019 (1 year 2 months) Bologna Area, Italy

- Developed modern websites with SEO, responsive mobile-first design, and performance using Laravel & WordPress

Freelancer.com
Junior Front-end Developer
August 2015 - March 2018 (2 years 8 months)
Ferrara Area, Italy

- Set up and customized websites to be beautiful, professional, highly functional, load guickly, and meet high SEO requirements

Education

Università degli Studi di Ferrara Bachelor of Science - BS, Computer Science · (2017 - 2022)

PANELLA I.T.I.S

Infromatica & Telecomunicazione, IT · (2013 - 2016)

Free Code Camp

Full Stack Web Development Certification, Computer Software Engineering · (2015 - 2016)